

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a 26 year old **computer engineer** currently based in Pretoria. I have a penchant for solving problems using software and digital circuitry. I have close to **4 years of experience** in the defence and aerospace industry primarily as an embedded **systems developer** and **signal analyst**. I'm passionate about the development of systems and enjoy working with people who share this passion.

EDUCATION

2005 - 2009	National Senior Certificate (NSC) Sol Plaatje Secondary School
2010- 2014	B. Eng Computer Engineering (Distinction) University of Pretoria
2015- 2016	B. Eng Computer Engineering Honours (Distinction) University of Pretoria

PUBLICATIONS

 Cellphone 'fingerprints' can stop criminals Publication: Mail&Guardian

Published as part of the annual Mail&Guardian Science Voices competition. It gives an overview of the use of Specific Emitter Identification for identifying GSM cellphones.

- Agile System Development for Rapidly Prototyped
- Micro-UAV Surveillance System

Publication: International Council for System Engineers (INCOSE) 2015 Conference

Proceedings

This publication details the application of agile methods to the full scale engineering development of a UAV-based surveillance system.

 Specific Emitter Identification for Enhanced Access Control Security
 Publication: South African Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers (SAIEE) African Research Journal

This publication demonstrates the application of specific emitter identification or radio frequency fingerprinting to automated gate remotes as a means of protecting these gates against replay attacks.

tel: +27832913245

email: jeevanninansamuel@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jan 2014 - Jul 2016

Denel Dynamics: Junior Engineer

I worked as a developer for GPS & inertial navigation systems used for missile guidance. My key responsibilites included development of embedded software development, application software development, modelling and simulation, as well as systems engineering.

Aug 2016 - Present CSIR Contractor: RF & Signal Processing Engineering

I work as a developer for electronic warfare receivers, specifically instantaneous frequency measurement (IFM) receivers. My key responsibilities include RF engineering, systems engineering, development of automated test facilities and software.

SKILLS & CAPABILITIES

Programming		
Python	0000000	
C++, C	000000	
C#	000000	
Octave, Matlab	000000	
Java	000000	
HTML, CSS	000000	
Documentation		
LaTeX	000000	
Microsoft Word	000000	
Languages		
English	Fluent	

AWARDS

- Best Final Year Project in Signal Processing
- · Denel Dynamics Overall Highest GPA for 2014
- Greatest Young Systems Engineers of the Year Winner



Gaming & Game Development



Coffee



Machine Learning & Analytics



Movies & Series



Exploring Music &
Music Production



Learning



Art & Design